happy world tourism day everybody who's
watching listening and it gives us great
pleasure to bring one of our regular
collaborators on a Sheena Kapoor is head
marketing corporate Communications and
CSR at ICICI at Lombard they've been
worthy Partners over the years on our
get some sun property which a lot of you
love listening to or you travel
enthusiasts and remember wherever you go
you must have travel insurance wonderful
to see you how are you and thank you for
being kind enough to come to our radio
station I have this chat oh thank you so
much Rishi and I think the pleasure is
all yours
absolutely I'm just kidding but no I'm
I'm equally excited to be here
um thank you so much
tourism I assume the whole new dimension
and when it comes to ensuring safe
tourism
what do Travelers have to keep in mind
when they're looking for travel
insurance I think that would be a good
place to start and how does ICICI
Lombard make sure its insurance plans
address those important factors in its
offerings right so I think all of us you
know and you spoke about travel
enthusiasts all of us love to travel
whether it's for business or pleasure or
vacation and one realizes that actually
if you really want to have complete
Security and peace of mind travel
insurance is a necessity and
unfortunately in India
um the penetration is very low even
though the awareness seems to be on the
higher side people know that they should
take a travel insurance but a lot of
times customers don't because they see
it as you know as unnecessary expense
but however travel insurance is a
necessary
um you know purchase simply because
there a lot of uncertainties or twists
in the tail that could come when you're
traveling you could have trip
cancellations you could have you know an
illness you could have been struck with
covid while you were traveling as we
have seen in the past two years uh there
could have been an unfortunate accident
you could even lose your passport or
personal belongings
um or your baggage you know so there are
multiple things and uncertainties where
uh you are left vulnerable as a traveler
you and your family or your friends and
therefore those are the situations that
as a travel insurer we cover and so that
you can travel safely enjoy or travel or
vacation and leave all the worries to us
that's lovely leave all the worries to
us I'd like to actually now get into
case studies individual
occurrences instances uh you know
experiences that people have had to face
where I see I say Lombard has come true
for them and these are not just
something that I've been jawed up these
are actual happenstances things which
have happened during Travelers lives and
something really important happened uh
you know not in a very nice way for a
Mumbai resident who is traveling to
Thailand for a holiday
around about the time covid-19 was still
prevalent and I'd like you to talk about
how you came through for somebody uh
who's your your partner your
collaborator somebody who bought your
travel insurance yeah um as a customer
um I can I can share a few incidents
um how you know we've really come and
that's really as an insurer that's the
moment of truth to actually see whether
the partner is there by your side has
your back when you actually really need
it right during the claim so um this
particular customer was actually Mumbai
based and traveling to Thailand and this
was in Jan last year when um he was
struck with kovid and that meant that he
had to actually be admitted in Thailand
for about 10 days
um and I say I said Lombard because he
was a policy holder we enabled an entire
seamless experience so that the entire
hospitalization and the treatment was
cashless and making sure that the
patient and our customer is well taken
care of so there's no hassle about
running around trying to get and even in
international markets as you can well
imagine the treatment cost and the whole
medical cost can actually be very
inflationary in nature and can actually
cause a big dent in your pocket so to
that extent it's it's always advisable
to be well protected well secured and I
say Lombard here was you know one such
incident where we stood by you know our
customer side
um I I could I could share and you know
one-on-one is being afflicted by illness
by a virus like the covert virus but
there are so many times something just
completely unforeseen happens
you might be going on a foreign vacation
and an accident happens of fall happens
and I'm given to understand that a a
person who who held icsa and Lombard
travel insurance was traveling from
Delhi to Canada uh the point of last
point of uh disembarkation being Toronto
this is Delhi Zurich Montreal Toronto
and he or she had a fan of fall of
fracture
yes
um again very unfortunate uh scenario
and you know but
these incidents don't come knocking as
predicted right life is unpredictable
and and that is what insurance is to
take care of the uncertainties and the
unpredictabilities of nature
um in this case the customer actually by
accident had a fall and actually
fractured both the legs which meant that
the customer actually needed a surgery
an urgent surgery but obviously a
surgery of this kind of Orthopedic
nature would necessitate a longer
post-operative care and the patient was
actually
um you know the customer had actually
planned for a 30
um or a three month uh window so it's a
90-day window uh travel period but was
very clear that wanted to have the
surgery in India so that he can be
looked after even from the
post-operative care and you know didn't
want to be in Canada at that point in
time so again
um you know because uh he was on ICS
Lombard policy whole folder we enabled
an entire evacuation and repatriation
back to India uh seamlessly uh covered
the expenses because he had the
insurance cover and ensured that he gets
his treatment here in India like he
wanted and necessitated the entire
experience quite seamlessly again
cashless cashless and as per the needs
of the person purchasing the insurance
as opposed to straddling them with lots
of rules and regulations I remember
as a family of forward we traveled to
Sri Lanka a lot of our Journeys were
these long winding Coastal roads
or you know the the railway
because it's a small country Colombo is
developed I think they're just about
building the airport at candy at the
time
um so some countries especially a small
island nations which are very very
beautiful Road Transport might be the
only way out or perhaps one of two ways
out and that God forbid would lead to
some eventualities and I believe you did
have a case like that yes uh this one is
is actually very tragic
um and very unfortunate
um this was a family of five traveling
to Sri Lanka and like you said were
wanting to take
um buy the car and Road Transport so
that they're able to enjoy the scenery
and the Landscapes uh but unfortunately
oh they met with an accident so the car
toppled over and very sadly actually
left three members of the family
deceased
um and obviously you know it was a very
traumatic experience for the customer
um and one can't even begin to Fathom or
imagine the kind of state of duress you
know that the family would be in and
you're in a foreign land
um so we um because you know again he
was insured and was our customer uh we
actually designated a local agent uh
first and foremost to ensure that the
entire hospitalization for the two
um and the treatment is cashless we also
ensured that all the assistance with
respect to evacuation of you know the
survivors as well as the remains of the
deceased family members were brought
back to India so the entire
evacuation the cashless
hospitalization treatment and just the
comfort of a local agent being there who
understands your pain and anguish and to
whatever extent was able to take at
least the logistical worries out of your
head you know so to that extent uh and
very sad experience but I think it yet
again undermines the importance and the
value of being well insured especially
on on travel since we're talking travel
but even otherwise you know whether
you're talking motor or health or you
know business insurance or even life
insurance before I round up this section
and go to the next part of our
conversation
as a formula one fan I was I was
Crest Fallen when Martin Schumacher had
a skiing accident and I was like man why
did this have to happen millions of fans
around the world felt that way I know
for a fact that I see I say Lombard will
cover you for travel irrespective of
whether it's business or Adventure
travel so I think that'd be a nice point
to sign off I mean somebody wants to go
on a skiing uh holiday to Switzerland or
you know the Alps
how one can opt for a policy depending
on the nature of your trip Oh yes
totally so Insurance travel insurance
is flexible is customizable
and it is customizable to the needs of
the traveler based and dependent on the
activity that the traveler is initiating
you mentioned an adrenaline junkie for
instance a ski diver it could be a
bungee jumper
um if and foremost you are revealing the
activity that you're going to be
undertaking uh in a foreign location you
have cover specially catering to that
um for instance you could even have a
cruiselet cover if you wanted to cover
on you know any kind of accidents or
cover that you need while you're
stranded on a cruise
you could have
um you know even
um a bail bond cover oh God forbid if
you were to caught up in some League
issues in a foreign country and you know
it could just be out of pure innocence
or ignorance of the local rules
um there is cover that we enable for
that
um you know and and there are like I
mentioned customization that you can do
on multiple aspects uh we have insurance
cover ranging from up to five lakh USD
even in terms of the age demographics we
can cover age groups of starting a
three-month-old infant uh to as high as
an 85 year old uh person or a senior
citizen
um also the policy enables you to not
undertake any kind of Prior medical
checkup or examination you can do that
up to the last minute that you're
actually booking your tickets even up to
at the airport you could buy an
insurance policy and it's very seamless
literally just a click away
um so we've enabled all these platforms
even on the digital side you know
through our mobile through our WhatsApp
uh through a 24 7 uh support
um through an AI uh agent uh chat board
all of these to make it a very digital
seamless uh purchase of the insurance
itself it's a world tourism day
especially Sheena Kapoor head marketing
corporate Communications and CSR at icsa
Lombard has joined me on the show now to
the next part I mean Concepts like
worktation workation it's a combination
of working navigation communication and
pleasure which is business and Leisure
all of this has gained so much traction
not just with Gen Z lingo but also what
we went through in the pandemic I mean
people now want to work wherever they
want to work are there any Innovative
Insurance products from icsa Lombard
that you believe could reshape the way
people perceive travel coverage and how
you're adapting your Insurance Solutions
to to cater to these changing
preferences you're right and speaking of
pleasure maybe the next time we could be
having this interview in Maldives to
pick on Margaritas you know if both our
companies allowed it
but uh yes I I think uh these have been
the recent Trends in travel
um one is the whole Revenge travel that
has really kicked in uh ever since kovid
and being marooned for two years you
know in the Comforts of your home
um and post opening today you know the
fairs have exponentially risen the
airfares you will find most hotels on
full capacity especially around
seasonalities
um the trend of digital Nomads uh what
covet really proliferated was the
ability to actually work out of
practically and remotely out of any
location uh which has led to the
vocations you know so you combine
vacations and work especially for the
digital Nomads and pleasure because a
lot of the you know Travelers we see
um you know and I'm sure you could
relate to that and and so could the
listeners even if you were to travel
overseas you know on work trip typically
you would want to extend the a work trip
by another few days just to be able to
get the local culture nuancing and you
know enjoy
you know the cafes and and that's the
Leisure aspect which is dovetailing the
business aspect
um so from
um an insurance lens uh one is of course
you know to reinforce and reiterate the
entire plethora of uncertainties that go
along with the uh you know the nature of
the Beast which could be trip
cancellations or delays or
um you know loss of baggage or even a
passport
um or it could be you know
hospitalization that you may need but
what we've also done over and above this
um is you know for instance
a lot of the times you made for instance
a pleasure a trip you may want to do
multi-trip kind of a travel right you're
going to multiple destinations on that
one tour we have actually enabled
insurance cover which ranges from three
days up to six months 180 days which you
can pretty much choose customize uh
depending on how many days you need it
during the term and you could use that
for a you know period of one year and it
doesn't matter how many trips you take
during that one year basis you know the
kind of coverage that you've taken on
the number of days you could take n
number of trips during those six months
and
irrespective of the destination
irrespective of the frequency and you
could switch it on and off while you are
in that destination so that's the kind
of feature like a Mobile roaming Garden
yeah yes listen as World tourism day
how do you and the brand Envision deeper
collaborations between the insurance
sector insurance providers and the
tourism industry and I'd like it if you
could give some examples of how such
Partnerships enhance the the overall
travel experience for customers
right I I think not just on world
tourism day but yes it's an inflection
point or to be able to pick up the
subject and talk more passionately and
uh emphatically about this but the whole
ecosystem of travel which includes your
Airlines your travel agencies tour
operators your
um you know uh platforms which are your
ticketing platforms and booking
platforms it's about and and of course
the insurers uh it's about all of us
coming together to be able to one uh
educate the need for travel insurance I
think it's very important that we keep
emphasizing on the importance that this
is this is not something which is uh you
know an unnecessary Surplus it is not
and literally if you talk about uh even
from a costing perspective
um it's one tenth of the cost if you
travel overseas it could push you back
anywhere between between 2 lakhs to 7
lakhs depending on the kind of travel
and stay and the numbers of families
that you're traveling for and the
destination literally one tenth of that
would be your travel insurance so you're
talking about a cover for the peace of
mind and security for that entire trip
and to be able to safeguard yourself
against any kind of
um unfortunate incident that may occur
um literally maybe you know for two
thousand three thousand rupees in the
overall sense it's it's very minuscule
for the kind of peace of mind that you
could get so it's about a lot of
education and awareness in informing and
educating the customers on the need I
think the second is about being able to
give a package and bundled product of
travel insurance uh as in when the
customer is planning their travel or is
booking their tickets
um it's also about you know working
closely with the insurers to be able to
provide customizable or flexible options
so for instance if there are Travelers
like you mentioned you know on on the
Adrenaline Junkies we were wanting to do
some you know um say extreme sports or
you know which need that kind of uh
coverage for say a sports related
injuries or loss of equipment
um you know you could cater to policies
that cover those aspects
um and over and above this it's about
also you know it you know I think
working closely with the regulator and
the industry to hopefully in the years
to come make this mandatory to travel at
least for international which today it
isn't but I think that would be a big
um you know a propeller to actually
drive penetration for travel insurance
but after actually thank you and your
team for this next question
because it's given me a very interesting
idea for perhaps the next season of the
season after next of get some sun which
is our challenge so really it's so
important sustainable travel practices
and you know today more than ever before
people are asking the right vital
questions and for those of you who are
listening watching normally one has a
discussion with the person one is
interviewing or their team saying what
are things we can you know pick up as
talk points and this is something that
the icse Lombard team was very uh was
very very keen on exploring And
discussing and kudos to them so I'd like
you to talk about
ICICI Lombard's efforts to align its
travel insurance offerings with
sustainable travel practices and any
initiatives or strategies that are aimed
with supporting the eco-conscious
traveler alongside of course providing
that that comprehensive coverage that
you've been talking about no sure I I
think not just in travel but in a lot of
um you know uh spaces especially in
organizations and boardroom agendas one
finds the entire sustainability
ESG aspects taking more and more
prominence in discussions and it stems
from you know individuals and
organizations as corporate citizens
trying to build a Greener more
sustainable world for ourselves and for
the generations to come and really
respecting the planet and in case of
travel you know when you travel
especially for the nature lovers you
know when you're traveling to
um you know a lot of these beautiful
destinations where you have these
gorgeous stunning Landscapes it's about
bringing the consciousness of
co-inhabiting and coexisting with nature
even if you went for a wildlife safari
not disturbing the balance the Natural
Balance of the ecosystem about actually
signing up for hotels which are
eco-friendly you know they may have
renewable energies they may have
um you know equal
bedding they may have even a Wigan or
organic food options
they may have even electric vehicles for
a transport even from a transport
perspective you know trying to discover
and explore uh the location and
destination on foot you know so that a
you know you're not adding to the you
know climate and the pollution uh
perspective but you're also being fit
and you're able to actually also take in
a lot more nuances of the cultural and
the local Cuisines or the sightseeing
and you're able to appreciate the beauty
a lot more closely even on airlines for
instance you know Airlines is you know
obviously the carbon footprint attached
with them is very high so trying to
reduce that by trying to opt for either
direct flights or you know at best
One-Stop layovers so that you're able to
reduce the kind of Air transport that
you have or you know you mentioned even
in country is like you know Sri Lanka
trying to use the local railway and the
public transport itself or to be able to
get a better again you know a local
understanding and I appreciate the
nuancing a lot better and I think it
enriches your experience so much more
you know and you can you know say to
yourself that okay I've
I've tried to reduce my carbon footprint
and leading a more sustainable Choice
consciously in life well remember to
thank us because I'm going to put you
onto a Blog on the icic Lombard website
it's icsclumbart.com
and if you actually go to the blog
section there is a plan your
eco-friendly holiday the budget-friendly
way which is a Blog on the website and
along with that just a subtle message
for you guys to follow the icslumbar
insurance
a Twitter handle Instagram page as well
as Facebook page they're very active on
social media and obviously I'm not just
social media I mean let's talk about
technology and digital tools that you
have and you meet such rapid strides
over the last decade to improve the
accessibility the convenience the
effectiveness of travel insurance
services
yeah I I think uh it's a euphemism to
say that you have to be digital first
you know I I think that is now really in
uh integrated into the very ethos and
the core DNA of
um as an organization of ICS alone but
um so on the textile we've made uh huge
leaps um and there was slew of
initiatives
um and I could talk about that but you
know sticking to the travel insurance
aspect
um one is the entire access uh and
availability of travel insurance you
know through a very digital seamless
platform to the customer whether it
literally just a few clicks away you
want to buy it on the website you would
like to take it up on the I'll take care
app or you can chat on WhatsApp uh with
Ria um you know we have a responsive uh
intelligent agent
um so the entire process of purchase is
actually very digital and seamless then
you come to the claims aspect the claim
aspect also is extremely seamless when
AI LED so literally you get your even
the policy document is issued you know
in an e-form and on a claim settlement
uh in in case you did have to have to go
through that you could pretty much just
chat on WhatsApp and the AI at the back
end would be able to flag off where you
are in the journey help you in the
resolution of the claim settlement and
also uh by when your claim would be
settled and by what amount you know to
that level of integration uh we use AI
in a lot of real-time assessments as
well from a risk perspective
um you know we are using AI on the
travel and and that's futuristic but you
would see that there are a lot of new
emerging risks today you know especially
with uh Global uh you know climatic
conditions so you could have political
risks you could have emerging climate
risks and those are the AI tools that
we're using to actually also look at and
assess the risks on the emerging side
and to be able to do assessment of
pricing uh accordingly
um and there is data that we work on
real time in association with some of
our travel operators and agents to
actually keep
um the well-being of the traveler and
the customer Paramount and foremost you
know when I look at ICICI Lombard's
travel insurance portfolio there are a
few things you covered in this interview
for example you said you talked about
trip cancellation you talked about
Cruise cover for maritime Journeys you
talked about medical covers Hospital
medical evacuation repatriation that
you've been doing
but just a couple of these features
which I find quite fascinating I find
fascinating bail bond cover I'm not
going to talk about that and of course
the loss of valuables you know
electronic equipment personal money uh
you know those colors right so
um again you know bail bond cover is to
be able to actually provide you a cover
in in a situation and hopefully nobody
should really need it but in a situation
where you run into some legal hassles in
a foreign country
um because you're not aware of the local
laws and you're not aware of the rules
and regulations and you may actually end
up you know indulging in a very innocent
uh gesture or activity not knowing and
unwittingly you know may have crossed
certain boundaries which are
unacceptable and therefore a bail bond
cover is to be able to provide you that
kind of cover from a legal hustle
you know and penal measures of course
it's a lot more complex than that and
would differ from case to case so that's
one example of the bail bond cover
um the other aspects like I mentioned
you know we cover policies that cover a
loss of baggage it could be you know
loss of passport loss of jewelry it says
about my electronics yeah yeah you know
my husband was traveling a few years ago
in to Italy and in Milan the day he
landed he got my coach you know
he got marked then you know was without
his wallet thankfully you know the
insurance cover and a local friend was
there to help but you just have these
completely unforeseen scenarios that may
occur
it's an international tourism Day
special with Sheena Kapoor head
marketing corporate Communications and
CSR and icsa Lombard we're entering the
home stretch of this interview so I know
actually what he said was made a lot of
sense so you said it's not just about
International tourism day you do all
these things through the year this is
fabulous you know it's like women's day
and why shouldn't we celebrate it
absolutely but still since it is a
rational tourism day I'd like you to
just skim through uh how you plan to use
this wonderful occasion to help promote
safe and enjoyable trouble
so again
um we are hoping uh on this day to
actually
educate our customers on the importance
of travel insurance and the need for uh
travel insurance
um you know some sort of travel tips
through a Blog and content about how
they can make
um you know curated experiences and
travel a lot more interesting uh from an
experience standpoint
um also you know we have done our recent
survey and study on the research side
which has some interesting insights and
Trends related travel insurance
um you know and we'd like to bring that
again to the media and
um you know to the Forefront
um you know and I'll give you a simple
example the the level of awareness for
travel insurance is is about quite high
it's it's in the range of 70 to 75
percent uh although the penetration is
very low and then we looked at you know
so certain age groups and we found what
were the kind of inflection points and
the tendency and propensity to buy
insurance for these demographics as well
as by destination so there are these
interesting Contours and I think on the
world tourism day uh it's a function of
our content both on the resort side
insights as well as educating customers
and building more awareness overall
travel travel safely and travel
completely peacefully uh you know leave
your worries behind and let us be your
invisible travel partner on the journey
so I'm going to actually sign off with
very get some sunesque
this is a program that icse Lombard has
been kind enough to support over the
years and one of the reasons people tune
into the show is where to go to
and you have some very interesting
statistics about top international
travel destinations as of now as we
speak and the factors influencing travel
insurance purchase and almost like a
quality to that
I'm curious is the life stage of a
consumer have any impact on the purchase
intent I mean for example you could be
single uh you know you could be a couple
you could have a larger family nuclear
family I don't know so I think that'll
be a nice way to sign off top travel
destinations and you know those
statistics now I think before I get to
that Rishi you touched upon get some sun
and I have to say like this is now seven
years that we've been Associated and
collaborated uh you know on get some sun
with radio one and I think uh it's a
it's a successful uh collaboration
simply because it has actually a a
combination and accumulative impact of
the Trinity as I call it so there's you
and radio one you know and you've got
your loyalist uh listeners and the
content and the music uh playlist is is
absolutely uh top of the line and and
actually a lot of it I resonate very
strongly with my playlist on a daily
basis
um this the second being you know um the
ranveer's thing of course so who of
course brings his uh you know very
inimitable style and uh very unique
style of beat the Sutra dhar and
protagonist and bringing alive a lot of
his own experience of travel and you
know the conversations and trying to
build a lot more content which is very
engaging and enriching and exciting and
third of course Isis Lombard we as you
know as the largest private insurer of
the country I think we are well placed
uh to talk about travel insurance and um
and I think therefore this Trinity uh is
great in fact I I should also let you
know that uh our recent brand track
Studies have shown a very high index of
awareness of get some sun as well as a
very high Affinity score for this
program so there are a lot of people who
know about this and we have data now to
prove and who like it coming to your
actual question on the actual statistics
um so yes you're right our studies
actually proved that about 74
of travelers from the north actually uh
North India are they take travel in
Florence
more towards destination like Europe
um followed by southeast Asia Middle
East we've seen as a destination for
some strange reason
um you know a lot of customers have a
lower propensity to take a travel
insurance Visa we as compared to say
Europe or southeast Asia uh you spoke
about family units and the life stage we
have found that about 84 percent of
individual or single household or
Travelers they have a likelihood and
intent to purchase the travel insurance
and this goes dramatically up as you
build your family Association so if you
are a couple it goes up to 92 percent if
you are a couple with kids if you're a
family the I think the responsibility
and the consciousness of you know taking
care of your family unit really kicks in
um and that jumps up Suddenly to 96 so
that's the kind of range that we've seen
uh you know even on the Travel Insurance
side with the intent to put purchase
please follow ICICI Lombard on Instagram
Facebook as well as Twitter go to the
website icslumbar.com it's really
exciting and vibrant and interactive uh
this is Shina Babu red marketing
corporate Communications and CSR happy
International tourism Day to all of you
you're listening to us on 94.3 Radio 1
in audio form and if you're watching us
on YouTube please subscribe this is the
radio one international uh YouTube
channel thank you so much thank you so
much likewise thank you so much thank
you
94.3 radio 1.